GONZALO FLORES

Orlando, FL

(407) 955-7944 | me@gonzaloaflores.com | My Portfolio

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

I am a Front-end Developer with expertise in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and related technologies. I am committed to delivering effective and user-friendly applications by focusing on details, finding solutions to problems, and communicating effectively.

EDUCATION

Frontend Developer Bootcamp

Frontend Simplified

BS in Biomedical Sciences

University of Central Florida

Certifications or Additional Education:

CS50: Introduction to Computer Science | Harvard University

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

Languages: HTML5 | CSS3 (+ SCSS, BEM) | JavaScript ES6+ | Typescript | Node.js Frameworks: React (+ hooks) | Next.js | Material-UI | Redux | Tailwind CSS Technology: NPM | Git | Yarn | React dev tools | Firebase v9 | GitHub

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer Support

Frontend Simplified

Supported 1,000+ students using HTML, CSS, Flexbox, JavaScript, and React best practices

- Utilized debugging best practices using Google Chrome inspect element tooling
- Simplified difficult programming concepts including responsive website development, CSS layout, Promises and API requests

Frontend Developer Internship

Sep 2022 - Dec 2022

Sep 2022 - Current

Frontend Simplified

- Transformed a completely static HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React single page application into an interactive user interface using animations, transitions and carousels
- Processed API requests with Axios to dynamically represent data from a cloud server and represented it through skeleton loading states, pagination and dynamic routing
- Utilized Git version control and the GitHub interface to work and thrive in a virtual and collaborative team environment

Abbott Laboratories Nov 2020 - Current

Medical Device Technical Support

- Provide first level support in troubleshooting customer complaints
- Receive calls and emails and address them in a professional and friendly manner
- Resolve and address any complaints or inquiries within the target timelines

PROJECTS

UltraVerse NFT World | Website | GitHub

Created a fully responsive NFT app integrating multiple APIs, React-Slick, and animated on scroll using CSS3.

YouTube Videos | Website | GitHub

YouTube Videos" is a responsive video app built with React and Material-UI that integrates the YouTube API to search and display videos, showcasing skills in API integration, responsive layout, and styling with Material-UI.

Twitter Clone | Website | GitHub

"Twitter Clone" is a social media app built with React that allows users to sign in, post tweets, comment, share, and message, demonstrating skills in OAuth authentication, API integration, and deployment to Firebase.

Hulu Project | Website | GitHub

"Hulu Project" is a full-stack web application that replicates the functionality of the popular streaming service Hulu. It was built using the Next.js framework and includes features such as browsing, searching, and managing a watchlist.

Internet Flicks | Website | GitHub "Internet Flicks" is a movie app built with React that allows users to search and filter through a list of movies, showcasing skills in responsive website development, API requests with Axios, and Git version control.

Library App | Website | GitHub

"Library App" allows users to browse and search for books, add books to a virtual bookshelf and cart, and checkout. The project was developed using the React JavaScript library and demonstrates my ability to work on e-commerce websites.

QR Wizard | Website | GitHub

"QR Wizard" is a web application for generating QR codes using the React JavaScript library. It allows users to easily generate QR codes for a variety of purposes, such as storing contact information or linking to a website.

Personal

SOFT SKILLS Excellent verbal and written communication skills.

Strong attention to detail, with the ability to catch and correct errors before they impact the final product.

Proven ability to analyze and solve complex problems in a timely and effective manner

Strong interpersonal skills, with the ability to build and maintain positive relationships with colleagues, clients, and stakeholders in order to achieve common goals

INTERESTS/HOBBIES

Mixed Martial Arts, Boxing & Chess